Emmanuel Olatunji Olusegun emmanuelolusegun.co@gmail.com

6, Idowu Ajayi Street, Gbagada, Lagos State. (+234) Tel: 08039522075

OBJECTIVE: To attain professional distinction and proficiency that will provide leading edge services and solution to achieve my organisation corporate goals and missions.

SUMMARY

Two years professional experience in software engineering and testing using Visual JavaScript.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Js, C#, Java, CSS, HTML5, jQUery

Databases: SQL, MS Access, Firebase, MongoDB, Node

Tools: React, Redux, MS Visual Studio, Visual Source Safe, Vscode

Platforms: Mac, Windows 95/98/NT Networks: CGI Script, UNIX, HTML

Others: Design, Implementation and Coding

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Name: Wejapa, 03/07/2020 - 21/10/2020

Address: Lagos, Nigeria

Position: React Front-End Developer

Internship: Cert ID: WEJAPA0BEGAR2WL9BP9CLJ7GYY2020

Projects:

Project name: Chat App

Project Description: The application is a distributed application built using a Node.js server, and a browser client built in React, managing data using Redux

Project Duration: Involvement: 20/07/2020 – 14/08/2020

https://github.com/Olusegun-eo/WJRA-EP-0720

Projects:

Programming Duration: Four weeks

Responsibilities:

Designed and implemented the user interfaces (UI). Performed Unit Tests.

Specified and performed Feature Deliverables Test plans.

Coded The Components to verify the app behaviour.

Used: Js, React, Redux, VsCode, Mac OS,

Project name: Project Management Tools

Project Description: This is a simple project that helps to manage your project and you can login to a particular account and make your own project, firebase was used for managing authentication and firestorm for the database **Project Duration:** Involvement: 07/09/2020 - 19/10/2020

Programming Duration: Six weeks https://github.com/Olusegun-eo/projectManagementTools

Responsibilities:

Designed and implemented the user interfaces (UI).

Performed Unit Tests.

Specified and performed Feature Deliverables Test plans.

Coded The Components to verify the app behaviour.

Used: Js, React, Redux, VsCode, Mac OS, Firebase, Authentication

Service, firestore for database

IT CERTIFICATIONS: LAUTECH ICT

SCORES: Not stated

HONORS: Upper Credit, 2/08/2007

EDUCATION:

BTech in Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University, Ogbomoso, Nigeria, 07/2007-12/2012 GPA is 3.18

Project: K-means clustering Algorithm in image enhancement

Masters: Federal University, Uyo, Nigeria, —Current(On going)
Project: Privacy Preservation using K-anonymity Algorithm (A case

Study of Uyo Prison)

Secondary Education: Holy Micheal High School Ikirun, Osun state,

Nigeria, 1999-2005

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING: Project Management: Agile3

One year compulsory National Youth Service Corps

HONORS: Certified 25/06/13 - 24/06/2014

EXPERIENCE

Institution Worked with: National university Commission, Federal University of Technology Owerri...

Organisation: Northsouth Systems, Isolo Lagos.

Position: Computer Analyst and Accounting Consultant

Period: 2018 – January, 2019.

Duties:

Preparation of chart of Account Financial Statement of Position

Financial Statement of Performance Installation and management of software

Organization: Cita Petroleum, Nigeria Aviation Company, Uyo

International Airport Branch.

Position: Aviation Engineer Period: 2017 – 2018 Duties:

Into Plane Operation

Tank farming, draining and truck receiving

Operational management.

Loading and discharging

Data maintenance

AWARDS

National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) Skill acquisition and entrepreneurship workshop on Electrical maintenance 2013 Project Management with Agile3

Skills

Proficient in research study Software analysis and architectural design Proficient in computer

application such as Microsoft Word, Excel,
Power Point, e.t.c
Good Communications skills
Creative concept development / problem-solving skills
Dynamic personality with resourcefulness and flexibility
Ability to work independently as part of a team and across teams
Enthusiastic, versatile and work under pressure
Strong analytical skills and problem solving skill